Umesh Pal Singh

I am a professional developer with 12+ years of hands-on experience of building, implementing and developing applications and web based projects using a range of technologies and programming languages. Seeking to further improve skills level as the future in a challenging role as a full stack developer.

Work Experience

Lead Frontend Developer

Dec 2014 - Present

Indian Express Pvt Ltd.

- Lead a team of frontend developers in building and maintaining high-traffic web applications using React and NextJS.
- Spearheaded the adoption of modern frontend technologies and best practices, improving code quality and application performance.
- Managed project timelines, assigned tasks, and conducted code

UI Designer

Jan 2013 - Dec 2014

Dainik Jagran (Jagran New Media)

Designed visually appealing interfaces for web and mobile apps.

Collaborated with UX designers on prototypes. Implemented designs using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Conducted user research and usability testing to enhance user experience.

Web Designer

Dec 2011 - Dec 2012

Hodaki.com (Mortimer InfoTech Pvt. Ltd.)

Innovative UI Designer with experience in UX design and research, website layout, and interactive prototypes. Skilled in HTML, CSS, and Javascript. Designed inner pages for this as well. Like search, section, and Product pages.

Web Designer

July 2010 - Dec 2011

Prosoft Services (I) Pvt. Ltd.

Designed and developed responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Created wireframes and prototypes, collaborating with UX designers and developers. Conducted user research and usability testing to improve user experience and site performance.

Education

Bachelor of Arts

M.J.P. Rohilkhand University, Bareilly.

CMM (Comprehensive Multimedia) Diploma

Xplora Design Skool, Budaun (U.P.) (Affiliated by, Ahmedabad)

mrumeshyadav18@gmail.com

+91 9891 097 904

Ghaziabad, U.P., Indian

umesh-uiux.github.io

Skills & Competencies

JavaScript | jQuery | ReactJs | NextJs

HTML/CSS | Bootstrapping | Wordpress

REST APIs | Git | Github

Responsive Design | Redis | MongoDB MySQL | Cross-browser Compatibility SEO | VS Code | Adobe Photoshop, Figma

Projects & Portfolio

https://umesh-uiux.github.io/ https://www.behance.net/umeshpalsingh

Certifications

- Google Analytics Certification (GA4)
- HackerRank CSS Certification
- React (Basic) Certificate
- Problem Solving (Basic)

Achievements

 Top user and mentor of StackOverflow
 https://stackoverflow.com/users/783
 4362/umesh-singh

 Excellent Work Performance awards

Languange

Hindi Native English Moderate